The disguise surprise comedy of the year!
Victor/Victoria is a music, comedy, romance film directed by Blake Edwards.
A struggling female soprano finds work playing a male female
impersonator, but it complicates her personal life.
Victoria Grant, played by Julie Andrews.
King Marchand, played by James Garner.
Carroll "Toddy" Todd, played by Robert Preston.
Norma Cassady, played by Lesley Ann Warren.
"Squash" Bernstein, played by Alex Karras.
André Cassell, played by John Rhys-Davies.
Victor/Victoria is a 1982 musical comedy film written and directed by Blake Edwards and starring Julie
Andrews, James Garner, Robert Preston, Lesley Ann Warren, Alex Karras, and John Rhys-Davies.
The film was released by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, produced by Tony Adams and
scored by Henry Mancini, with lyrics by Leslie Bricusse.
The film was nominated for seven Academy Awards,
winning for Best Original Score.
It was a remake of the German film comedy Viktor und Viktoria shot
by Reinhold Schünzel in 1933 from his own script.
Victor/Victoria was adapted as a Broadway musical in 1995.
The film explores themes of paris, france,
cabaret, remake, cross dresser, soprano.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.